Chapter 13. Good progress.
Far into the night, while the other creatures slept, Charlotte worked on her
web. First, she ripped out a few of the orb lines near the center. She left the
radial lines alone, as they were needed for support. As she worked, her eight
legs were a great help to her.
So were her teeth. She loved to weave, and she was an expert at it. When she
was finished ripping things out, her web looked something like this.
A spider can produce several kinds of thread. She uses a dry tough thread for
foundation lines, and she uses a sticky thread for snare lines, the ones that
catch and hold insects. Charlotte decided to use her dry thread for writing the new message.
If I write the word terrific with sticky thread, she thought, every bug that
comes along will get stuck in it and spoil the effect. Now, let's see. The
first letter is T. Charlotte climbed to a point at the top of the left hand side
of the web. Swinging her spinteretses into position, she attached her thread
and then dropped down.
As she dropped, her spinning tubes went into action and she let out thread. At
the bottom, she attached the thread.
This formed the upright part of the letter T. Charlotte was not satisfied,
however. She climbed up and made another attachment right next to the first.
Then she carried the line down so that she had a double line instead of a
single line. It'll show up better if I make the whole thing with double lines.
She climbed back up, moved over about an inch to the left, touched her
spinterettes to the web, and then carried a line across to the right,
forming the top of the tea. She repeated this, making it double. Her eight legs
were very busy helping.
Now for the E. Charlotte got so interested in her work, she began to
talk to herself as though to cheer herself on. If you had been sitting
quietly in the barn cellar that evening, you would have heard something like
this. Now for the R. Up we go. Attach.
Descend. Pay out line. Wo. Attach. Good.
Up you go. Repeat. Attach. Descend. Pay out line. Wo girl. Steady now. Attach.
Climb. Attach. Over to the right. Pay out line. Attach. Now right and down.
And swing that loop. And around. And around. Now in to the left. Attach.
Climb. Repeat.
Okay, easy. Keep those lines together.
Now then, out and down for the leg of the R. Pay out line. Wo! Attach! Ascend!
Repeat! Good girl! And so, talking to herself, the spider worked at her
difficult task. When it was completed, she felt hungry. She ate a small bug
that she had been saving. Then, she slept.
Next morning, Wilbur arose and stood beneath the web. He breathed the morning
air into his lungs. Drops of dew catching the sun made the web stand out
clearly. When Lurvy arrived with breakfast, there was the handsome pig.
And over him, woven neatly in black letters, was the word terrific.
Another miracle.
Lurvy rushed and called Mr. Zuckerman.
Mr. Zuckerman rushed and called Mrs.
Zuckerman. Mrs. Zuckerman ran to the phone and called the arables. The
arables climbed into their truck and hurried over. Everybody stood at the pig
pin and stared at the web and read the word over and over while Wilbur, who
really felt terrific, stood quietly swelling out his chest and swinging his
snout from side to side.
Terrific, breathed Zuckerman in joyful admiration.
Edith, you better phone the reporter on the Weekly Chronicle and tell him what
has happened. He will want to know about this. He may want to bring a
photographer. There isn't a pig in the whole state that is as terrific as our
pig." The news spread. People who had journeyed to see Wilbur when he was some
pig came back again to see him now that he was terrific.
That afternoon, when Mr. Zuckerman went to milk the cows and clean out the
tie-ups. He was still thinking about what a wondrous pig he owned. Larvey, he
called, "There is to be no more cow manure thrown down into that pig pan. I
have a terrific pig. I want that pig to have clean, bright straw every day for
his bedding. Understand?"
Oh yes, sir, said Lurvy. Furthermore, said Mr. Zuckerman, I want you to start
building a crate for Wilbur, I have decided to take the pig to the county
fair on September 6th. Make the crate large and paint it green with gold
letters. What will the letter say? asked Lurvy. They should say Zuckerman's famous pig.
Lurvy picked up a pitchfork and walked away to get some clean straw. Having
such an important pig was going to mean plenty of extra work. He could see that.
Below the apple orchard at the end of a path was the dump where Mr. Zuckerman
threw all sorts of trash and stuff that nobody wanted anymore.
Here in a small clearing hidden by young alders and wild raspberry bushes was an
astonishing pile of old bottles and empty tin cans and dirty rags and bits
of metal and broken bottles and broken hinges and broken springs and dead
batteries and last month's magazines and old discarded dish mops and tattered overalls.
and rusty spikes and leaky pales and forgotten stoppers and useless junk of
all kinds, including a wrongsized crank for a broken ice cream freezer.
Templeton knew the dump and liked it.
There were good hiding places there, excellent cover for a rat, and there was
usually a tin can with food still clinging to the inside.
Templeton was down there now, rumaging around. When he returned to the barn, he
carried in his mouth an advertisement he had torn from a crumpled magazine.
"How's this?" he asked, showing the ad to Charlotte. "It says crunchy. Crunchy
would be a good word to write in your web."
"Just the wrong idea," replied Charlotte. "Couldn't be worse. We don't
want Zuckerman to think Wilbur is crunchy. He might start thinking about
crisp crunchy bacon and tasty ham. That would put ideas into his head. We must
advertise Wilbur's noble qualities, not his tastiness. Go get another word,
please, Templeton. The rat looked disgusted, but he sneaked away to the dump and was
back in a while with a strip of cotton cloth.
How's this? He asked. It's a label off an old shite. Charlotte examined the
label. It said pre-shrunk.
I'm sorry, Templeton, she said. But pre-shrunk is out of the question. We
want Zuckerman to think Wilbur is nicely filled out, not all shrunk up. I'll have
to ask you to try again. What do you think I am? A messenger boy? grumbled the rat.
I'm not going to spend all my time chasing down to the dump after advertising material.
Just once more, please, said Charlotte.
I'll tell you what I'll do, said Templeton. I know where there's a
package of soap flakes in the woodshed.
It has writing on it. I'll bring you a piece of the package.
He climbed the rope that hung on the wall and disappeared through a hole in the ceiling.
When he came back, he had a strip of blue and white cardboard in his teeth.
"Eh," he said triumphantly. "How's that?" Charlotte read the words. "With new radiant action."
"What does it mean?" asked Charlotte, who had never used any soap flakes in her life.
How should I know? said Templeton. You asked for words and I brought them. I
suppose the next thing you want me to fetch is a dictionary.
Together they studied the soad with new radiant action, repeated Charlotte
slowly. Wilbur, she called. Wilbur, who was asleep in the straw, jumped up. Run
around, commanded Charlotte. I want to see you in action to see if you are radiant.
Wilbur raced to the end of his yard. Now back again faster, said Charlotte.
Wilbur galloped back. His skin shone.
His tail had a fine tight curl in it.
"Jump into the air!" cried Charlotte.
Wilbur jumped as high as he could. Keep your knees straight and touch the ground
with your ears, called Charlotte. Wilbur obeyed.
Do a back flip with a half twist in it, cried Charlotte. Wilbur went over
backwards, writhing and twisting as he went.
Okay, Wilbur, said Charlotte, you can go back to sleep. Okay, Templeton, the
soapad will do, I guess. I'm not sure Wilbur's action is exactly radiant, but it's interesting.
Actually, said Wilbur. I feel radiant.
Do you? said Charlotte, looking at him with affection. Well, you're a good
little pig, and radiant you shall be.
I'm in this thing pretty deep now. I might as well go the limit.
Tired from his romp, Wilbur lay down in the clean straw. He closed his eyes. The
straw seemed scratchy, not as comfortable as the cow manure, which was
always delightfully soft to lie in, so he pushed the straw to one side and
stretched out in the manure. Wilbur sighed. It had been a busy day, his
first day of being terrific.
Dozens of people had visited his yard during the afternoon, and he had had to
stand and pose, looking as terrific as he could. Now he was tired. Fern had
arrived and seated herself quietly on her stool in the corner. "Tell me a
story, Charlotte," said Wilbur, as he lay waiting for sleep to come. "Tell me a story."
So Charlotte, although she too was tired, did what Wilbur wanted.
Once upon a time, she began, "I had a beautiful cousin who managed to build
her web across a small stream. One day, a tiny fish leaped into the air and got
tangled in the web. My cousin was very much surprised. Of course,
the fish was thrashing wildly. My cousin hardly dared tackle it, but she did. She
swooped down and threw great masses of wrapping material around the fish and
fought bravely to capture it. "Did she succeed?" asked Wilbur. "It was a never
to be forgotten battle," said Charlotte.
"There was the fish caught only by one fin, and its tail wildly thrashing and
shining in the sun.
There was the web sagging dangerously under the weight of the fish. "How much
did the fish weigh?" asked Wilbur eagerly. "I don't know," said Charlotte.
"There was my cousin slipping in, dodging out, beaten mercilessly over the
head by the wildly thrashing fish.
Dancing in, dancing out, throwing her threads, and fighting hard. First she
threw a left around the tail. The fish lashed back. Then a left to the tail and
a right to the midsection.
The fish lashed back. Then she dodged to one side and threw a right and another
right to the fin. Then a hard left to the head while the web swayed and
stretched. Then what happened? asked Wilbur. Nothing, said Charlotte. The
fish lost the fight. My cousin wrapped it up so tight it couldn't budge.
Then what happened? asked Wilbur.
Nothing, said Charlotte. My cousin kept the fish for a while and then when she
got good and ready, she ate it. Tell me another story, begged Wilbur. So
Charlotte told him about another cousin of hers who was an aeronaut.
What is an aeronaut?" asked Wilbur. "A balloonist," said Charlotte. "My cousin
used to stand on her head and let out enough thread to form a balloon. Then
she'd let go and be lifted into the air and carried upward on the warm wind."
"Is that true?" asked Wilbur. "Or are you just making it up?" "It's true,"
replied Charlotte. I have some very remarkable cousins.
And now, Wilbur, it's time you went to sleep.
Sing something, begged Wilbur, closing his eyes. So Charlotte sang a lullabi
while crickets chirped in the grass and the barn grew dark. This was the song she sang.
Sleep, sleep, my love, my only deep, deep in the dung and the dark. Be not
afraid and be not lonely. This is the hour when frogs and thrushes praise the
world from the woods and the rushes.
Rest from care, my one and only, deep in the dung and the dark. But Wilbur was
already asleep. When the song ended, Fern got up and went home.
Chapter 14.